sadlierconnect.com 2014-12-02

# Sadlier Connect™ - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

William H. Sadlier, Inc. ("Sadlier", "we" or "us"), the operator of this web site, is committed to preserving the privacy of those who visit our site - Sadlier Connect, located at http://www.sadlierconnect.com ("Site"). This document will outline how we gather and utilize various sources of information obtained during your visit to the Site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected at this Site. By using or accessing the Site, you signify your assent to our Privacy Policy. **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE.**

Personal and Non-Personal Information

We have been retained by your school district ("District") and/or school ("School") to provide online educational services via the Site. Your District or School oversees the Site and, accordingly, has control over who can register for an account and who can use various features of the Site.

Districts and Schools are able to create and register administrative accounts ("Administrator Accounts") for their Districts/Schools and the administrators, employees and/or staff designated by each District/School (collectively, "Administrators"). Administrators will also be able to register additional accounts for their District/School teachers (collectively, "Teacher Accounts"), and their students ("Student Accounts"), and the parents of their students ("Parent Accounts").

Teachers in each District/School (collectively, "Teachers") may create their own Teacher Accounts for the Site and may be able to register Student Accounts and Parent Accounts for their students and the parents of their students.

In order to create or register for an account or utilize some of the services on the Site, you may be asked to provide, or you may choose to upload, certain personally identifiable information about yourself, your student(s) or their parents (collectively, "Personal Information"). The following Personal Information may be collected when registering for and/or utilizing the Site:

  * Administrator Accounts: Personal Information collected by the Site may include the first, middle and last name, email address, school name, username, password or other information provided by or associated with the Administrator Account holder.

  * Teacher Accounts: Personal Information collected by the Site may include the first, middle and last name, email address, school name, username, password or other information provided by or associated with the Teacher Account holder.

  * Student Accounts: An Administrator or a Teacher may register a Student Account on behalf of his/her student and assign the Student Account a username and password. When registering the Student Account, the Site may collect the following Personal Information about the student: (i) student's first, middle and last name; (ii) student's ID; (iii) student's grade level; (iv) school name; (v) username; and (vi) password. The Site will assign the Student Account a username, which the Administrator or Teacher can change upon registration or the student can change upon logging into the Site. The Administrator or Teacher is responsible for maintaining Student Account information. After registration, registered students will be able to access the Site by logging into the Site with the student's applicable username and password. The Site will allow students to communicate via the Site's internal message system with their Teachers and Administrators. Students will be able to submit assignments to their Teachers via the Site and their Teachers will be able to assign assignments and grades to their students via the Site. Each School is responsible for obtaining parental consent for its students to use the Site. If a parent has any questions regarding registration, please contact your child's Teacher or School Administrator.

  * Parents Accounts: An Administrator or a Teacher may register a Parent Account on behalf of his/her student's parents and assign the Parent Account a username and password. When registering a Parent Account for a specific School, the Site may collect the following Personal Information about the parent: (i) parent's first, middle and last name; (ii) parent's email address; (iii) student's first, middle and last name; (iv) student's ID; (v) student's grade level; (vi) parent's username; and (vii) parent's password. The Site will assign the Parent Account a username, which the Administrator or Teacher can change upon registration or the parent can change upon logging into the Site. The Administrator or Teacher is responsible for maintaining Parent Account information. After registration, registered parents will be able to access the Site by logging into the Site with the parent's applicable username and password. Parents will have access to and will be able to view his/her child's assignments and any internal messages to or from his/her child, and will be able to track his/her child's progress on the Site. The Site will allow a parent to communicate via the Site's internal message system with his/her child's Teachers and Administrators. If a parent has any questions regarding registration, please contact your child's Teacher or School Administrator.

With respect to all accounts, we do not collect any Personal Information about you unless it is voluntarily provided by you.

In addition, in order to support the internal operations of the Site, we may also collect nonpersonally identifiable information, such as IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, duration and frequency of visits, and other data, and may aggregate any information collected in a manner which does not identify any individual ("Aggregate Information").

Information Usage

We will use the Personal Information that we collect solely for the use and benefit of the School, including providing the Site's educational services to its registered accounts. We do not use the Personal Information we collect for commercial purposes not related to the provision of the services requested by the School. For instance, we do not use any Personal Information in connection with online behavioral advertising or building user profiles for commercial purposes. Nor do we sell any Personal Information to third parties or mass marketers.

Only we and our affiliates, our technical consultants, third party auditors and other third parties who make our Site available, enhance its functionality, or provide associated services and/or who deal with you in delivering content have access to this information, and we require them to agree that they are covered by this policy.

Please note that, though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, Sadlier reserves the right to and may disclose Personal Information about you in response to (a) requests from local, state or federal law enforcement officials; (b) any judicial, administrative or similar proceeding or order, such as subpoena; (c) if required by law; or (d) to investigate suspected fraud, harassment, physical threats, or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, the Site rules or policies, or the rights of third parties or to investigate any suspected conduct which we deem improper. Please also note that we do reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers of Site assets.

Use of Cookies

The Site may pass a "cookie" (a string of information that is sent by a web site to be resident on your system's hard drive, and/or temporarily in your computer's memory blocks). The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a particular page. The Site may use cookies to support the internal operations of the Site, such as allowing you access to passwordprotected areas of the Site. You may set your browser to decline cookies. If you do so, however, you may not be able to fully experience some interactive features of the Site.

Children's Online Privacy

We are dedicated to the privacy of children, particularly children under 13 years of age. This Site is not intended for registration by children, including any children under the age of 13, and we have no intention of allowing children to register accounts for themselves for the Site. If a child under 13 has registered an account for him/herself on this Site, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database. Please note, however, that there are sections of this Site that children may access without registration (including sections where children can play games and download materials) and we do not collect Personal Information from children on these sections of the Site.

If a parent or legal guardian would like to refuse to allow any further collection or use of their child's Personal Information, please contact your child's Teacher or School Administrator. If the request is made to us directly, we will direct you to your child's Teacher or School Administrator to validate the request and respond accordingly.

We are dedicated to maintaining the privacy of all students, whether under 13 or older, in accordance with applicable laws. In this regard, we will maintain any and all Personal Information in education records which come into our possession in accordance with the requirements of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA"), and will not disclose such information to third parties except with the consent of a parent, the School or an eligible student (as applicable), unless otherwise permitted under FERPA and its associated regulations.

Links to Third Party Sites

Our Site may contain links to other web sites, including our affiliated or co-branded web sites. Other web sites may also reference or link to our Site. These "other" domains (web sites) are not controlled by Sadlier. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. We do not endorse, screen or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other web sites. Visiting these other web sites is at your own risk.

Security 

Sadlier will not be liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. We have undertaken all commercially reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized Internet access to visitor data retained in our servers, however, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, Sadlier cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided online, and you do so at your own risk. Users must accept all risks associated with any data transmission, including the risk that their personal information may be intercepted in transit.

Policy Modifications/Opt-Out

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use Personal Information in a way that differs from this policy, we will post such changes here. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes. Please check this page periodically for changes to this Privacy Policy.

If you would like to remove Personal Information from our Site, please contact your Teacher or Administrator. We are not responsible for a Teacher or Administrator's failure to remove your Personal Information, including in a timely manner, as that is the responsibility of the applicable School/District. If an Administrator would like to delete an Administrator's Account, please contact us at [support@sadlierconnect.com.](mailto:support@sadlierconnect.com)

Site Terms and Conditions

Use of this Site is governed by, and subject to, the legal notices contained at www.sadlierconnect.com/termsandconditions. Your use, or access, of the Site constitutes your agreement to be bound by these provisions. **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE.**

Contact

If you have any questions about Sadlier Connect's Privacy Policy you can contact:

Webmaster  
William H. Sadlier, Inc.  
9 Pine Street  
New York, NY 10005   
212-227-2120

Fax 212-267-8696

United States of America

Our Site is maintained in the United States of America. By using the Site, you authorize the export of Personal Information to the USA and its storage and use as specified in this policy.

**Effective Date:** This Privacy Policy is effective and was last updated on March 25, 2014.
